







Sr Engineering Manager - vCenter R&D seeking roles in IT Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Solution Designing, Product Development, Software Architecture, Core Java, C++, JIRA, Agile, Scrum



Total Experience: 17 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Current Designation: Senior Engineering Manager

Current Company: Vmware Software India Private limited (till

Feb 2020)

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Sr Engineering Manager - vCenter R&D, Project Manager - IT/ Software, IT Project Management, Requirement

-Gathering, Solution Designing, Product Development, Software Architecture, Core Java, C++, JIRA, Agile, Scrum

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

#### Summary

Engineering leader well versed in all aspects of project and personnel management. Led teams responsible for delivering key content in VMware vCenter server software. Experience in collaborating with customers, product management, architects, cross-functional teams. Experience in providing technical guidance, career development and mentoring to team members.

# **Work Experience**

- Vmware Software India Private limited (till Feb 2020) as Senior Engineering Manager Jun 2010 to Till Date
- VM ware as Sr Engineering Manager, vCenter R&D Jun 2010 to Feb 2020

Real Time Stats Monitoring System (vStats 1.0) / Team size - 10 / Golang

vStats is the vCenter next-gen stats management platform. Developed as a service in vCenter, its objective is to provide real-time monitoring capabilities with a long-term goal of supporting advanced use-cases like analytics and capacity planning.

Collaboration - Engagement with product management/architect/customer to scope requirements, drive public API, drive system design and implementation.

Execution - Planning and estimation, identifying and managing risks, prioritize backlog, translate goals to user-stories with acceptance criteria, manage sprints, maximize team velocity.

Mentoring - Regular 1:1, broadcast communications with engineers at different levels to set, to upskill and meet their career and performance goals.

Hiring - Hiring for team expansion and onboarding of new engineers.

(Public api - https://developer.vmware.com/docs/vsphere-automation/latest/vstats/

Infrastructure for vAPI Tasks in voxd / Team size - 2 / C++

Project objective was to provide an internal implementation of VAPI interface for tasks module in vpxd. This is part of the core infrastructure for vpxd. Aim was to re-design task-related infrastructure, supporting querying capabilities and expose them as VAPI.

Responsibilities were planning, estimation, task allocation, tracking and addressing any technical issues. The service was developed in C++

(Public api - https://developer.ymware.com/docs/vsphere-automation/latest/cis/tasks/)

vCenter Data Provider / Team size - 4 / C++

Project objective was to provide querying capabilities directly from vpxd. Part of this task was to develop and relay custom set of properties in vpxd to higher layers which would ultimately be consumed by the UI.

Responsibilities were to lead a team of 5-engineers and work as part of a global team with the architects in defining and developing these custom set of properties which spanned the VC inventory. Day-to-day responsibilities were task planning, estimation, allocation, tracking and to resolve any technical issues.

### vCenter modules sustenance / C++

## **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Sustenance of the modules related to task-infra, stats-mgmt, NFC, KV-Store.

Responsibilities are to provide support for regression testing, customer escalations, address technical debt. Team also participates in global guru duties for bug triaging. The server code is in C++ and test code in Java.

Projects as Engineering Manager/Individual Contributor -

VCQE Testware

This is a Java based homegrown test framework which extensively covers Core VC, Storage and Networking related testing areas. It is used by close to 25+ teams in VMware including System Testing. I have contributed as a manager and IC to this framework.

Inventory Service - Tagging and Authz / Team size - 3 / Java

Manage the QE efforts for Tagging and Authz services testing. Tagging is a feature which allows to define tag categories and tags that can be attached to any entity like a VM, Host. Authz is a service for privilege associations and definitions to these entities. Responsibilities were to understand the feature, work with the dev to provide Test Specifications and Plans, do the implementation, reviews using VCQE and monitor regressions. Currently these services are part of vpxd-svcs in the VCSA

Host Profiles / Team size - 3 / Java

Manage the QE efforts for the host profiles feature and have contributed as an IC. Host profiles allows application of a configuration profile to ESX. Responsibilities were to understand the feature, collaborate with the dev, lead and contribute to the testing efforts. Tasks involved providing Test Design Specifications and Plans, implementation using VCQE and monitoring regressions.

#### Patni Computer Systems as Software Specialist

Dec 2002 to Jun 2010

Projects at Patni

Client - VMware, Inc, PA

Worked as contractor at VMware, vCenter QE org. Some of the projects done were testing of VM creation and provisioning api, Host Configuration and operations related api. Responsibilities were to test the VMODL1 api for these areas and to monitor regressions.

Client - St. Jude Medical Systems

Tech Lead for this project. Objective was to design and implement an E2E Eclipse plugin which would allow the customer to draft and execute a custom language test script for pacemakers. We developed support and environment for a formal language that would allow a domain expert to specify and run a test script on these pacemakers. About 30k+ existing manual test scripts were ported to this new system.

Client - Hitachi

Tech Lead for this project. Objective was to provide a web-interface to browse their extensive product portfolio that was exposed internally to multiple departments and to third-party customers.

^ Back to Top

#### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Physics) from Mumbai University in 1998

PG: MCA (Computers) from Mumbai University in 2002

^ Back to Top

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C++	
JIRA	
CORE JAVA	

^ Back to Top

#### **Affirmative Action**

# Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

lo Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.